Accommodation Related Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ) | Xiamen University Malaysia
Skip to main content
Accommodation Related FAQ
Accommodation Services
Accommodation Related FAQ
Text
Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ)
1. Application and Booking
Text
1.1.ááááHow do I apply for student accommodation?
The University offers accommodation to active and full time students of the University.
For new students, room allocation will only be processed once the applicant has accepted an offer to study at Xiamen University Malaysia.
To secure accommodation (subject to room availability), all completed application forms must be submitted to the Accommodation Office no less than two (2) weeks prior to the commencement of the new semester.
1.1.1.ááááRequest Residence Application Form by contacting
studentaccommodation@xmu.edu.my
.
1.1.2.ááááSubmit the completed Residence Application Form together with the payment slip of residence application fee via email to
studentaccommodation@xmu.edu.my
.
1.2.ááááWhat is the residence application fee?
Upon submission of residence application form, each application must be accompanied with the payment of residence application fee of RM 100 (non-refundable).
The application can be paid via:
1) á áCheque or Bank Draft payable to ô
XMU JIAGENG EDUCATION DEVELOPMENT SDN BHD
ö; or
2) á á áBank Transfers:
Bank name: Public Bank Berhad
Account Name: XMU JIAGENG EDUCATION DEVELOPMENT SDN BHD
Account Number: 319-724-8410
Branch: KL City Main Office
Branch Address: Menara Public Bank, 146 Jalan Ampang, 50450, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia
Swift Code: PBBEMYKL
Bank Name: Maybank Banking Berhad
Branch: KLIA 2
Account Number: 5624-3250-5328
Swift Code: MBBEMYKL
Branch Address: Retail Lot L3-1, Level 3, Gateway KLIA 2, Sepang, Selangor, Malaysia
Bank Name : China Construction Bank (Malaysia) Berhad
Branch: KL Main
Account No. : 696-000-440-003 (USD currency)
Swift Code : PCBCMYKL
Bank Address : Level 20, Menara CCB, Quill 6, No 6, Leboh Ampang, City Centre, 50100, Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia
1.3.ááááCan I choose my preferred room type?
The room type can only be an option as stated on the provided residence application form.
All accommodation applications are subject to room availability and the University reserves the right to assign any other type of accommodation available.
2. Fees and Payment
Text
2.1.ááááAre there any deposits required?
Successful applicants are required to pay a deposit of RM 500 (refundable) together with one semester rental upon check-in.
Any request for cancellation or premature termination of the tenancy after check-in will result in the forfeiture of all rentals paid.
2.2.ááááWhat is the payment schedule for student accommodation rental?
Rental payment is to be made on a per-semester basis.
Student residents are required to pay for accommodation rental fees within seven (7) working days from the commencement of the new semester.
2.3.ááááAre utility charges paid separately by students?
Student residents will be billed for their electricity consumption on a monthly basis. Electricity charges per month per unit will be borne equally by all residents in that same unit if the unit is occupied by more than one resident.
Payment shall be made to the Finance Office during the said period of time. A late payment charge of RM10.00 per month will be imposed after 30 days of the billing date.
3. Check-In, Check-Out and Tenancy Related Questions
Text
3.1.ááááWhen are the designated check-in and check-out times for accommodation?
Check-in and check-out are available on weekdays during office hours (9.00 AM to 5.00 PM) and/or within the announced period.
3.2.ááááAre any documents required for the check-in process?
Students are required to present valid personal identification documents and fill in the provided check-in documents upon check-in process.
3.3.ááááWhat is the process for terminating a tenancy and completing the check-out procedure?
Any request for cancellation or termination of the tenancy is allowed after a minimum stay of one (1) semester by giving the Accommodation Office at least a one-month written notice. The one-month written notice must be emailed to
studentaccommodation@xmu.edu.my
. Failing to do so will result in a penalty equivalent to one-month rental and/or forfeiture of deposit.
Student residents are responsible for being aware of their tenancy period, which corresponds to the academic calendar of their respective programme.
Tenancy at the residence will be terminated automatically if the resident is no longer a bona fide full time student of the University.
Student residents must fill in the check-out documents at the end of their stay at university residences. Proper check-out procedures refer to student residents shall vacate the room and return the rooms keys together with the room air conditioner remote controllers (If required) by submitting check-out documents to the Accommodation Office during office hours.
Upon withdrawal or termination, residents are to ensure that their units are clean and shall remove all their belongings from the units, failing which; the University and its management shall remove their belongings from their rooms without liability.
4. Facilities
Text
4.1.ááááWhat facilities are provided in the room?
All rooms are provided with:
-ááááBed frame and mattress
-ááááWardrobe
-ááááStudy table and chair
-ááááAir conditioning (Monthly rental is excluded electricity bill)
-ááááWi-Fi
-ááááEn-suite bathroom (Including water heater)
Student residents are required to provide their own bedsheets and bedding materials (e.g. pillows, blankets, etc.), and must use bedsheets on the mattress at all times, as these items are not supplied by the University.
4.2.ááááWhat general facilities are available to student residents?
- A common pantry is located on each floor, which is equipped with a microwave oven, a refrigerator and a water dispenser.
- A laundry room
- 24/7 Safety and Security
-áCanteens conveniently situated adjacent to the residential blocks
- A five-storey Student Activity Centre features a variety of facilities, including a canteen, convenience store, gym, swimming pool, prayer rooms, and more.
4.3.ááááWhere can I find more detailed information about the hostel facilities?
Comprehensive information and photographs about the hostel facilities and room types is available in the Xiamen University Malaysia Accommodation Photobook (include the link to the file) and Virtual Tour (include website link).
General Virtual Campus Tour
Click Here
5. On-Campus Accommodation Rules and Regulations
Text
The University reserves the right to make amendments without prior notice and as such shall not be held liable in respect of the said alterations.
All student residents residing in the residential blocks under the purview of Xiamen University Malaysia are governed by the UniversityÆs accommodation policies and regulations. For full details, please refer to the Xiamen University Malaysia Residences Management Rules and Regulations (
Download
).
Additional Information
On-Campus Accommodation
Apply On-Campus Accommodation
Accommodation Sections & Documents
Accommodation Related Enquiries
Frequently Asked Questions (FAQ)
