ECA Clubs & Societies | Xiamen University Malaysia
Skip to main content
Extra-Curricular Activities (ECA) Department
Unleash Your Potential
Clubs & Societies
1. Sports
Fuel your competitive spirit and stay active by joining one of our many sports clubs. From basketball and badminton to martial arts and ultimate frisbee, there's something for every level of athletic ability.
Badminton Club
Swimming Club
Acrux Cheerleading Club
Football Club
Martial Arts Club
Basketball Club (Sharks)
Table Tennis Club
Tennis Club
Volleyball Club
Track & Field Club
Fitness Club
Outdoor Adventure Club
Kendo Club
Chess Club
Blaze Dodgeball Club
Ultimate Frisbee Club (Krakens)
E-Sport Club (Vulcan)
Scuba Diving Club
Yoga Club
2. General
Explore a wide range of interestsùfrom photography and public speaking to entrepreneurship and environmental awareness. These clubs provide a platform for students to develop new skills, engage in meaningful discussions, and connect with peers who share similar passions. Ideal for those looking to grow personally and socially outside the classroom.
Board Games Society
XMUM Business Association
Chinese Debate Society
English Language Society
Math Society
Photography Society
Speak-T Society
Environmental Club
Astronomy Club
X-Tech Club
Robotic Club
Rubik's Club
Coding Club
AI Club
3. Performing Arts
Show your talent in music, dance, or drama! Join clubs that light up the stage with performances, concerts, and creative showcases.
XMUM Philharmonic Orchestra (XMPO)
Music Club
Ukulele Society
Yanan Chinese Orchestra (YCO)
Dance Club
Drama Society
24 Festive Drums Club
Diabolo Club
4. Culture & Arts
Explore creativity and global perspectives through culture, art, and expression. Connect with others, share ideas, and bring diverse worlds to campus life.
Visual Art Club
Nanqiang Calligraphy Society
Chinese Society
Christian Fellowship Club
Traditional Chinese Medicine Society
Buddhist Society
Korean Cultures & Arts Society
ACG Research Society
Tea Club
Coffee Club - The Brewix
Muslim Society
Handcraft Society
5. Service & Volunteerism
Make a difference through community service and social impact initiatives. These clubs empower students to give back, raise awareness, and become agents of positive change.
First Aid Society
AIESEC
Omega Leo Club
Rotaract Club
Youth Leader Association
6. International Communities
Experience a global community right on campus. Our international community help students celebrate their cultural identities while fostering cross-cultural understanding and global friendships.
International Student Ambassador (ISA)
XMUM Yemen Student Community
XMUM Central Asia Student Community (CASC)
XMUM Indonesian Student Community - Garuda Dwi Pantara (GADPA)
Use Sliding Banner?
Off
Off
