Counselling Service | Xiamen University Malaysia
Skip to main content
Counselling Centre
Campus Life
Counselling Centre
Text
Counselling Service
XMUM Counselling Centre values the diversity of all students and aims to promote the mental well-being of our students at the University. We strive to meet the unique needs of each student who comes for counselling service irrespective of age, socioeconomic status, ethnicity, culture, religion, gender identity, and sexual orientation.
The Counselling Centre provides individual and group counselling to support our students at the University. Our licensed counsellors are available to listen to you and talk through any personal challenges or emotional concerns that you might have during your study life. This free service ensures the confidentiality and privacy of all students.
Text
Image
Text
We provide support for:
Adaptation
Self-exploration
Study stress
Emotion
Grief and loss
Sexuality/Gender
Family
Boy-Girl relationship
Friendship
Career guidance
Text
To make an appointment, please fill in the form:
https://forms.office.com/r/thC285mjta
Alternatively, students may visit Counselling Centre in room B1-110 during office hour for further assistance.
