Campus Email | LINC
About
A3 Library Details
The People Great Hall
Meet The Team
Library Floor Directory
Contact Us
A3 Library Tour
Virtual Tour
XMUM Website
News & Event
Gifts-in-Kind
Services
Book Services
Loan & Return
Fines & Report Lost
Purchase Request
Document Delivery
Learning Services
Moodle
Turnitin
Computers
Printing
Scholarly Work
E-Resources
Library E-Resources
OPAC
E-Books
E-Journal
Technologies
Campus Services
Campus ID & E-Card
Campus Email
Online Storage
E-Services
IT Services
Network & Connectivity
Data Centre
Microsoft 365
Learning Technology
Guidelines & Policy
Library Policies
IT Services Policies
Spaces
Makerspace
About Makerspace
How to Apply for Makerspace
Makerspace Safety Guidelines
Makerspace Rules and Regulations
Makerspace Calendar
Instruction Room
Mini Cinema (with 3D)
Room Types Available
Campus Electronic Mail
Campus Email
Campus Electronic Mail
Campus Email
Campus usersÆ email address and initial password will be provided during student registration (student) or on-boarding (staff).
All campus usersÆ Email address will be set in the following format, example:
CampusID@xmu.edu.my
Sign in through
https://www.office.com
. Users will need to change the provided initial password upon the first login. Note: always logout the application every time after using.
After signing in, click on gear icon
on the top right corner of the page to customize your email and office365 settings (change operating system language, location or time zone setting, change password, menu, and other options). On the same page, you will see various apps and icons that allow you to access your
Outlook
(Email), Calendar, Cloud Storage, Office Online and other applications. You can also click on the
icon for æHelpÆ options.
To set your time zone for your Campus Email Outlook and Teams Calendar, click the gear icon in the top right. Under Language and time zone click Change your language. Scroll down to the Region, Time zone section and click the pencil icon next to the time zone to edit. Search or scroll to find your time zone and click the Select button.
The University will use campus email as one of the communication channels to make announcements and etc. Do check your campus email frequently for all University announcements and information.
All users is able to access campus email using Microsoft 365 Outlook and other Microsoft 365 valuable cloud services. [Refer
Microsoft 365
]
However, please be reminded
your campus email address will be inactivated and eventually be removed immediately, once you have left or graduated from the University.
Thus, do archive your important email or data regularly if requires, while your campus email account is still active.á (
Note:
The University does not take any responsibility for the recovery of saved files or data loss on all Microsoft 365 applications and services. Thank you for your understanding and cooperation.)
Changing Initial Password for Email
Sign in through
https://www.office.com
Enter your email address and the initial password, and key in your new password and click æConfirm PasswordÆ to change. Click æUpdate PasswordÆ and sign in again.
Show Me
Forgotten Password for Email
How to Reset Campus Email Password
In Campus (Library/Email/AskA)
1. Visit
Library Circulation Counter (A3 2nd Floor)
and
show your Campus ECard/IC/Passport
for identity verification purposes, or
2. Email
it@xmu.edu.my
,
attach with a softcopy of yourCampus ECard/IC/Passport
for identity verification purpose, and your personal email address info, in order to further assist on password reset request, or
3. Raise an AskA
app.xmu.edu.my/aska
and
attached with a softcopy of your Campus ECard/IC/Passport
for identity verification purpose.
Off Campus (Email/AskA)
1. Raise an AskA
app.xmu.edu.my/aska
and
attached with a softcopy of your Campus ECard/IC/Passport
for identity verification.
Note: New password must be strong password, which maintain an 8-character minimum length requirement, with the use of multiple character sets i.e. uppercase and lowercase characters, number or symbol.
Changing Email Password in Office 365
Sign in through
https://www.office.com
Refer
How to Change My Campus Email password
How to Archive Your Emails?
Export emails, contacts, and calendar items to Outlook app using a .pst file.áThe messages that you keep in a .pst file are no different from other messages. You can forward, reply, or search through the stored messages as you do with other messages.
Click
here
for the steps by steps guides on how to archive your emails.
How can I avoid phishing email scams?
Always be on alert for phishing emails.
What is Phishing Email?
Phishing attacks are the practice of sending fraudulent communications that appear to come from a trusted, reputable or legitimate source. It is usually performed through email. The goal is to steal sensitive data such as personal information, login information, account password or to install malware on the victimÆs machine. Phishers or hackers frequently fake the identities of higher-level departments, leaders, colleagues, IT admin etc., and send emails to trick email users into entering account passwords on their forged websites such as campus email system or websites.
How does phishing work?
Phishing starts with a fraudulent email or other communication designed to lure a victim. The message is made to look as though it comes from a trusted sender, such as
From your university or bank. If it fools the victim, he or she is coaxed into providing confidential information often on a scam website or link provided. Sometimes malware is also downloaded onto the targetÆs computer.
Phishing emails usually come with a hyperlink that trick you to a spoofed website or trick the receiver into sharing personal information like account passwords, credit card information, etc.
Email and text messages that appear to be legitimate but actually contain dangerous links, attachments, or lures that trick their targets into taking an unknown, risky action.
In Brief
Phishers frequently use emotions like fear, curiosity, urgency, and greed to compel recipients to open attachments or click on links. It often sent to create urgency and panic receivers to take immediate action, e.g. your account was infected by viruses, your account was hacked, etc.
Claims that email receiver will lose your account if immediate action was not taken.
Phishing attacks are designed to appear to come from legitimate companies and individuals.
Cybercriminals are continuously innovating and becoming more and more sophisticated.
It only takes one successful phishing attack to compromise company network and steal your data, which is why it is always important to have better awareness on this scam.
Be alerted of any potential phishing email receives in your campus email address, especially emails that have an aggressive tone or claim that immediate action must be taken to avoid repercussions should be considered a potential scam.
Avoid sending passwords, bank account numbers, or other private information in an email.
Avoid clicking links in emails, especially any that are requesting private information.
Be wary of any unexpected email attachments or links, even from people you know.
Look for æhttps://Æ and a lock icon in the address bar before entering any private information.
Have an updated anti-virus program that can scan email.
Change your campus email password, if you suspect your email password may have been compromised
Useful References:
https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/security/threat-protection/intelligence/phishing
https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/windows/protect-yourself-from-phishing-0c7ea947-ba98-3bd9-7184-430e1f860a44
Should you have any doubts on the email received, forward the email to
it@xmu.edu.my
for checking, then delete the message from your inbox.
Technology Services
Campus ID & E-Card
Campus Email
Online Storage
Office Documents
Network & Connectivity
Data Centre
Microsoft 365
Learning Technology
Library Contact Information
Xiamen University Malaysia Library
A3 Building
Jalan Sunsuria,Bandar Sunsuria,
43900 Sepang, Selangor
Phone : 03-8800 6801
Email : librarian@xmu.edu.my
