Network & Connectivity | LINC
About
A3 Library Details
The People Great Hall
Meet The Team
Library Floor Directory
Contact Us
A3 Library Tour
Virtual Tour
XMUM Website
News & Event
Gifts-in-Kind
Services
Book Services
Loan & Return
Fines & Report Lost
Purchase Request
Document Delivery
Learning Services
Moodle
Turnitin
Computers
Printing
Scholarly Work
E-Resources
Library E-Resources
OPAC
E-Books
E-Journal
Technologies
Campus Services
Campus ID & E-Card
Campus Email
Online Storage
E-Services
IT Services
Network & Connectivity
Data Centre
Microsoft 365
Learning Technology
Guidelines & Policy
Library Policies
IT Services Policies
Spaces
Makerspace
About Makerspace
How to Apply for Makerspace
Makerspace Safety Guidelines
Makerspace Rules and Regulations
Makerspace Calendar
Instruction Room
Mini Cinema (with 3D)
Room Types Available
Network Connection Services
Network & Connectivity
Network Connection Services
Network & Connectivity
Wireless Access (WIFI)
The campus building areas are fully covered by the campus wireless network signal. Users caná access the WIFI network through the UniversityÆs Central Authentication System (CAS) and where it obtains an IP address and configuration setting automatically via DHCP. This wireless network enhancement has been implemented on 27th Mar 2026 for Student WIFI SSIDs and will be gradually roll out to the Staff WIFI subsequently.
1. Connect toá Wireless Network (WIFI)
û Students WIFI SSIDs areá ô
Student-5G
ö or ô
Student
ö. You will be automatically redirected to a login screen/page. Simply enter your Campus ID and password to authenticate. Once logged in, your device should remain connected for the duration of your session.
û Staff WIFIá SSID are ô
Staff-5G
ö or ô
Staff
ö, password to be advised by IT Department.
û International Academic Exchange Centre WIFI SSID is ô
XMU-IAEC
ô, password to be advised by IAEC staff.
2. If you would like to use your own wireless router, please seek approval from IT Department.
Note:
The Wifi name (SSID) for personal use cannot begin with ôXMUö nor using the same SSID names such as Guest, Staff, Student, etc.
3. Staff WIFI does not require user authentication as of now. However, in the later phase, user authentication will be imposed.
4. Internet access is provided by the University, currently it is
free of charge
.
Visit IT Office A3-103 (1F) during working hours, email IT at
it@xmu.edu.my
oráraise
AskA
, should you need further assistance.
LAN Network Access (Wired)
Wired/LAN connection is recommended for a more stable internet experience.
An Ethernet cable (RJ45) can be used to connect your computer to the LAN port (see picture).
Go to æNetwork and Internet SettingÆ > Choose æObtain an IP address automaticallyÆ
Set your network card to DHCP mode.
Currently, the campus network does not require user authentication. However, in the later phase, user authentication will be imposed.
Internet access provided by the University, is currently free of charge.
Secured Network Access
[A]
WebVPN (For In & Off Campus û All Users)
Visit URL
https://webvpn.xmu.edu.cn/.
You can login using Campus ID and Password, and accessing to WebVPN for E-Resource either from on campus or out of campus.
Note: Refer
Library E-Resources
for more information on E-Resource.
[B]
Connect Campus Systems via SSLVPN secured remote connection (For Off Campus û Staff only)
A secure remote access solution using campus SSLVPN with Remote Desktop Connection has been implemented by IT since September 2021.
XMUM SSLVPN secured remote connection system is only applicable for off campus staff to remotely access into XMUM campus system, using Staff campus ID and password only.
Note:
SSLVPN connection is only applicable for Staff only.
Staff can follow few simple steps in order to access to campus departmental systems securely.
Staff User Guides û
SSLVPN for Staff only
Alternatively, for student who may need to request for XMU SSLVPN remote access can filling up the online eform via URL:
SSLVPN Remote Access Online Request Form
û After submitting the eform, it will undergo a review and processing within five working days.
û For student SSLVPN request, student need to send supervisor approval letter via email to: ZGXS@xmu.edu.my and copy: IT@xmu.edu.my using studentÆs XMUM email.
û Upon submission of request, your application will be reviewed and processed accordingly within 5 working days.
û After request is approved, you will be guided on how to access for the SSLVPN.
û At the end of the access duration, IT will revoke access as necessary.
IP Phone (Telephony Services)
Campus IP Phones
1. XMUM IP telephony system uses Yealink IP Phone and Grandstream IP Phone as a standard phone set.
2. IP Phone system consolidates voice network and data network with following features, such as call waiting, call forwarding, call logs û user is reminded to clear the call history logs from time to time, voicemail, voice conference call û max 3 parties.
3. IP Phone can be relocated on any campus office network.
4. User can dial the campus IP phone numbers using last 4 digits number for inter department communication.
How to request for the IP Phone
1. IP Phone (Deskphone) is applicable for
full time staff only mainly for office administrative, management and international staff
.á For installation arrangement, users can raise
AskA
and feedback on their convenience date and time to install the IP phone in their office, in advance.
2. IP phone is optional for lecturers and research staff as users are encouraged to consider using faster and online communication channels with students such as Microsoft Teams, wechats, whatsapp etc.
Should you require an IP phone, do fill the
IT Devices Installation Request form
, with justification of the need of IP phone and obtain HOD approval, prior to submit the signed request form to IT Department.
Upon approval, IT Department will install the IP phone in staff office, estimated in 3 working days and depending on stock availability. Upon installation, the phone number and default voice mailbox password will be communicated to user.
User to update phone extension for the admin team to process on name card accordingly.
3. After IP phone installation, ensure your phone line is reachable and able to receive incoming call or receiving call normally.
4. Users are encouraged on the sharing of IP phone within the same department (location), if feasible.
5. IP phone can be reassigned to another staff within the same department or return the IP phone set to IT Department (A3-103), if no longer requires.
Email
it@xmu.edu.my
or raise
AskA
, for further assistant.
Technology Services
Campus ID & E-Card
Campus Email
Online Storage
Office Documents
Network & Connectivity
Data Centre
Microsoft 365
Learning Technology
Library Contact Information
Xiamen University Malaysia Library
A3 Building
Jalan Sunsuria,Bandar Sunsuria,
43900 Sepang, Selangor
Phone : 03-8800 6801
Email : librarian@xmu.edu.my
