Historical Facts, Vision & Mission | Xiamen University Malaysia
Skip to main content
About Us
Home
Historical Facts, Vision & Mission
Facts of Xiamen University Malaysia
Text
XMU was founded by the Malayan Chinese Mr. Tan Kah Kee in 1921. Now 93 years later, XMU has reciprocated by setting up a campus in Malaysia, where Mr. Tan Kah Kee achieved great success in his career. This is a historic reciprocation.
Zhu Chongshi, XMU President (2003-2017)
Text
The Spirit Lives On
XMU founder Mr. Tan Kah Kee was considered a world-renowned educator who devoted all he had to the pursuits of education. XMUM solemnly pledges to uphold Mr. Tan Kah KeeÆs spirit of selfless dedication to the noble causes of education in establishing XMUM.
It will remain a not-for-profit institution; and not a sen will be repatriated to China. Instead, any surplus funds will be channelled back into research and scholarships for students of XMUM.
Text
Image
Text
Image
Text
Commitment to educational excellence
The establishment of XMUM sets new heights in the areas of cooperation and exchange in education between China and Malaysia. XMU is driven to build the campus into one of Malaysia's best, enriching Malaysia's tertiary education landscape to produce high-quality talents with international competitiveness.
Text
Vision
Mission
Xiamen University Malaysia aspires to become a university with a distinct global outlook, featuring first-class teaching and research, and embracing cultural diversity.
To nurture young talents with dignity and wisdom, turning them into fine citizens of the region who will contribute to the prosperity of the people and social progress of Malaysia, China and Southeast Asia.
