Campus ID & E-Card | LINC
About
A3 Library Details
The People Great Hall
Meet The Team
Library Floor Directory
Contact Us
A3 Library Tour
Virtual Tour
XMUM Website
News & Event
Gifts-in-Kind
Services
Book Services
Loan & Return
Fines & Report Lost
Purchase Request
Document Delivery
Learning Services
Moodle
Turnitin
Computers
Printing
Scholarly Work
E-Resources
Library E-Resources
OPAC
E-Books
E-Journal
Technologies
Campus Services
Campus ID & E-Card
Campus Email
Online Storage
E-Services
IT Services
Network & Connectivity
Data Centre
Microsoft 365
Learning Technology
Guidelines & Policy
Library Policies
IT Services Policies
Spaces
Makerspace
About Makerspace
How to Apply for Makerspace
Makerspace Safety Guidelines
Makerspace Rules and Regulations
Makerspace Calendar
Instruction Room
Mini Cinema (with 3D)
Room Types Available
Staff and Students Identification
Campus ID & E-Card
Staff and Students Identification
Campus ID & E-Card
Campus ID and Password Settings
Campus ID is a unique identification card for all staff and students.
Upon receiving the Campus ID, you need to access
https://id.xmu.edu.my
to reset/set the Campus ID password.
The link to set or reset Campus ID password will be sent to your
Campus Email Address > Outlook > Inbox/Spam/Junk
. You may set or reset password in the same URL above.
Video Tutorial
Subsequently, you can use the Campus ID and Campus ID password to login into multiple information service systems:
Borrow books, self-service printing, door access, discussion rooms booking, and VPN access
University learning portal û Moodle, Academic Affairs Online Systems, upcoming student portal and Turnitin (via Campus Email)
Campus ID (ECard) can be used in canteens, supermarkets, and for fine payment in Library.
You can get a replacement card free of charge only, if your card is stolen with police report presented, damaged or no longer works. Otherwise, there will be a lost card fee of RM30 imposed for the Replacement of Campus Staff / Student ID ECard.
For student
û email or visit B1-107 (Student Affairs Office) to report Campus/Student ID lost card and proceed to make payment in Finance office before submitting the card replacement form to IT.
For staff
û fill in the eForm
Staff ECard Replacement eForm
, proceed to make payment in Finance office to make payment of RM30, before submitting the card replacement form to IT.
Campus E-Card
Staff E-Card
Student E-Card
New and progress students need to upload photo by first week of new class commencement
, refer more details on
How to upload a photo for Campus ECard processing.
Note:
Your campus ID will be inactivated once you have left or graduated from the University. For further assistance, email
it@xmu.edu.my
or raise
AskA
. IT support will be attending to your request during working hours (Monday û Friday).
Technology Services
Campus ID & E-Card
Campus Email
Online Storage
Office Documents
Network & Connectivity
Data Centre
Microsoft 365
Learning Technology
Library Contact Information
Xiamen University Malaysia Library
A3 Building
Jalan Sunsuria,Bandar Sunsuria,
43900 Sepang, Selangor
Phone : 03-8800 6801
Email : librarian@xmu.edu.my
